The ultimate war between magic and science is about to begin.
The Flight of Dragons is a animation, fantasy,
family film directed by Jules Bass.
The realm of magic is being threatened by the realm of logic, so the
green wizard, Carolinus, decides to shield it for all time.
Ommadon, the evil red wizard, stands in his way.
Carolinus then calls for a quest that is to be led by a man named Peter
Dickinson, who is the first man of both the realms of science and magic.
It is Peter's job to defeat Ommadon.
Carolinus (voice), played by Harry Morgan.
Bryagh / Smrgol (voice), played by James Gregory.
Peter Dickinson (voice), played by John Ritter.
Sir Orrin Neville-Smythe (voice), played by Bob McFadden.
Princess Melisande (voice), played by Alexandra Stoddart.
Ommadon (voice), played by James Earl Jones.
The Flight of Dragons is a 1982 animated fantasy film produced
and directed by Jules Bass and Arthur Rankin Jr.
loosely combining the speculative natural history book of the same name (1979) by Peter
Dickinson with the novel The Dragon and the George (1976) by Gordon R.
It stars the voices of John Ritter, Victor Buono (in his final role before
his death), James Gregory, James Earl Jones, and Harry Morgan.
The film centers upon a quest undertaken to stop an evil
wizard who plans to rule the world by dark magic.
A major theme within the story is the question of
whether science and magic can co-exist.
This is told mostly through the experience of character Peter
Dickinson, drawn from the 20th century into the magical realm.
Released direct to video in the United Kingdom in September 1983, it was aired as an ABC "Saturday Night Movie" on August 2, 1986, and
released by Warner Brothers as a made-to-order DVD in the US on 17 November 2009 as part of the "Warner Archive Collection".
The opening song is sung by Don McLean.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
elves, wolf, magic, time travel.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.